<Position Division="Educational Services Division" Directorate="Learning &amp; Teaching" BusinessUnit="Arts, Sports &amp; Initiatives" Team="Arts Initiatives" PositionNumber="192653" Title="Arts Initiatives Advisor" GradeCode="SEO2" BriefRoleStatement="Directing the Schools Spectacular and support State Office personnel through the initiation, development, coordination and delivery of associated projects.">
  <StatementOfDuties>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Building the capacity of teachers through the development of professional learning opportunities and activities associated to Schools Spectacular and associated projects.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Contributing to unit-wide programs and planning as required.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coordinating the development and delivery of project plans for the Schools Spectacular and associated projects.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Directing the Schools Spectacular, developing its concept, chairing the creative team and coordinating related production and technical teams.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Liaising and negotiating with Public Schools NSW and external key stakeholders related to the Schools Spectacular and other related projects.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Overseeing the development and direction of staging and technical design of the Schools Spectacular.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preparing budgets, action plans, briefings, web materials and reports relating to the direction of the Schools Spectacular and associated projects.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SPECIAL CONDITION: Hours of work in the Arts Unit are currently determined in accordance with Determination No. 2 of 2011. At times Arts Unit employees are required to work in the evening and on weekends. A per annum allowance is payable to reflect these circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Supervising the work of related support staff.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</StatementOfDuties>
  <SelectionCriteria>
    <Criteria>Teaching qualifications and recent school based experience within the  K-12 range</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated commitment to participating in and managing accreditation processes</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven ability to liaise and negotiate with a range of stakeholders and work collaboratively within and across teams</Criteria>
    <Criteria>High level written and oral communication and interpersonal skills and experience in the preparation of documents including briefings, reports and correspondence</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated capacity to lead and supervise staff, monitor high standards and work effectively as part of a management team</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven ability to meet deadlines, provide sound advice and work independently </Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated capacity to ensure that projects are delivered on time, within budget and in accordance with agreed quality standards</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated ability to develop, plan and implement strategic initiatives and innovative practices that support education change for improved student learning outcomes</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Knowledge of and commitment to the Department's Aboriginal education policies </Criteria>
  </SelectionCriteria>
  <Admin>
    <Logo>C:\Projects\Application-shares\position-description\Assets\PdfTemplates\dec-pdf.png</Logo>
    <DocNumber>DOC17/27061</DocNumber>
    <LastUpdate>28/06/2017</LastUpdate>
    <ApprovedDate>26/06/2017</ApprovedDate>
  </Admin>
</Position>