<Position Division="Educational Services Division" Directorate="Learning &amp; Teaching" BusinessUnit="Arts, Sports &amp; Initiatives" Team="School Sports" PositionNumber="192691" Title="Leader School Sport Unit" GradeCode="CEO" BriefRoleStatement="Managing the operation of the NSW School Sport Unit and developing and implementing sports and related programs for government schools.">
  <StatementOfDuties>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coordinating school sport programs various levels including the Premier’s Sporting Challenge.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Liaising with other government departments, external sport organisations, major sponsors and the media.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Managing the operation of the NSW School Sport Unit.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preparing correspondence, reports and briefings for senior officers and the Minister.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Providing managerial support for the organisation of the School Swimming Scheme NSW Pacific Schools Games, and other special initiatives&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Providing statewide leadership in school sport.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reviewing and monitoring programs in school sport and providing strategic advice to senior officers on policy issues.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</StatementOfDuties>
  <SelectionCriteria>
    <Criteria>Tertiary qualifications and extensive current educational leadership experience</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated understanding of the professional standards and accreditation processes and capacity to manage systems supporting accreditation processes</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated superior liaison, consultation and negotiation skills with internal and external stakeholders in a politically sensitive environment</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated superior oral and written communication and interpersonal skills and the capacity to apply these to a wide range of reports, submissions and strategic planning</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Extensive knowledge and understanding of curriculum,  professional practice, policies, legislation, initiatives and current research in education at state, national and international levels</Criteria>
    <Criteria>High level management skills and experience, including leadership, people and resource management skills and the capacity to develop staff through the implementation of the Performance Development Framework</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Superior analytical skills and sound judgment with demonstrated skills to analyse performance and financial data, undertake reviews, evaluate and report on findings </Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven ability to initiate, research, develop and use performance information to design strategic plans, monitor and report on practices to drive improvement</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Capacity to lead staff in implementing the Department's Aboriginal Education and Training policies to ensure quality outcomes for Aboriginal people</Criteria>
  </SelectionCriteria>
  <Admin>
    <Logo>C:\Projects\Application-shares\position-description\Assets\PdfTemplates\dec-pdf.png</Logo>
    <DocNumber>DOC17/27636</DocNumber>
    <LastUpdate>26/06/2017</LastUpdate>
    <ApprovedDate>26/06/2017</ApprovedDate>
  </Admin>
</Position>