<Position Division="Educational Services Division" Directorate="Learning &amp; Teaching" BusinessUnit="Arts, Sports &amp; Initiatives" Team="School Sports" PositionNumber="192694" Title="Primary Sport PSSA Officer" GradeCode="SEO1" BriefRoleStatement="Coordinating statewide primary school sport programs. Act as the Executive Officer to the NSW Primary Schools Sports Association.">
  <StatementOfDuties>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coordinating and preparing NSWPSSA representative teams. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coordinating statewide primary school sport programs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drafting correspondence, reports, media releases and submissions. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Liaising with schools, the community and state, national and external sporting associations as required.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Providing executive support to the New South Wales Primary School Sports Association.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Providing policy advice on matters relating to primary school sport.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Supporting special initiatives and events in sport.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</StatementOfDuties>
  <SelectionCriteria>
    <Criteria>Teaching qualifications and recent school based experience within the  K-12 range</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated commitment to participating in accreditation processes</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated capacity to work collaboratively and liaise and negotiate with key stakeholders</Criteria>
    <Criteria>High level written and oral communication and interpersonal skills and the ability to maintain accurate and comprehensive written records</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Understanding of impact of technology on teaching and learning</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven ability to establish and lead teams</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven ability to work independently and as part of a team</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven successful experience in the planning, design, development, budgeting and evaluation of quality programs</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Knowledge of and commitment to the Department's Aboriginal education policies </Criteria>
  </SelectionCriteria>
  <Admin>
    <Logo>C:\Projects\Application-shares\position-description\Assets\PdfTemplates\dec-pdf.png</Logo>
    <DocNumber>DOC17/27974</DocNumber>
    <LastUpdate>26/06/2017</LastUpdate>
    <ApprovedDate>26/06/2017</ApprovedDate>
  </Admin>
</Position>