<Position Division="Educational Services Division" Directorate="Learning &amp; Teaching" BusinessUnit="Arts, Sports &amp; Initiatives" Team="School Sports" PositionNumber="192698" Title="Premier's Sporting Challenge Advisor" GradeCode="SEO2" BriefRoleStatement="Supporting the development and implementation of the Premier’s Sporting Challenges in Primary School and with particular responsibility for the delivery of the Sports Leadership Program.">
  <StatementOfDuties>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coordinating the development and implementation of the Premier’s Primary School Sport Challenge and assisting in&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coordinating the development of technology based programs to support the operation of the Premier’s Sport Challenges.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Developing and producing resource materials to support the Premier’s Sporting Challenges.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Establishing collaborative partnerships with individuals, key stakeholders and government and non-government agencies on matters relating to the Premier’s Sporting Challenges.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Preparing advice, correspondence and briefings on matters related to the Premier’s Sporting Challenges.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Providing high level advice on the implementation, management and operation of the Premier’s Sporting Challenges.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the development and delivery of the Premier’s Secondary School Sport Challenge.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</StatementOfDuties>
  <SelectionCriteria>
    <Criteria>Teaching qualifications and recent school based experience within the  K-12 range</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated commitment to participating in and managing accreditation processes</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven ability to liaise and negotiate with a range of stakeholders and work collaboratively within and across teams</Criteria>
    <Criteria>High level written and oral communication and interpersonal skills and experience in the preparation of documents including briefings, reports and correspondence</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Experience in the management of systems to analyse, record, manipulate, store and retrieve data</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Proven ability to meet deadlines, provide sound advice and work independently </Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated capacity to ensure that projects are delivered on time, within budget and in accordance with agreed quality standards</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Demonstrated ability to develop, plan and implement strategic initiatives and innovative practices that support education change for improved student learning outcomes</Criteria>
    <Criteria>Knowledge of and commitment to the Department's Aboriginal education policies </Criteria>
  </SelectionCriteria>
  <Admin>
    <Logo>C:\Projects\Application-shares\position-description\Assets\PdfTemplates\dec-pdf.png</Logo>
    <DocNumber>DOC17/31661</DocNumber>
    <LastUpdate>26/06/2017</LastUpdate>
    <ApprovedDate>26/06/2017</ApprovedDate>
  </Admin>
</Position>